(忆往昔)
别害怕黑暗  开玩笑吗
Don't be afraid of the dark? What, are you kidding me?
当然该害怕黑暗
Of course you should be afraid of the dark.
-你不知道外面有什么  -是牙仙
- You know what's out there. - It was the tooth fairy.
-爱尔兰小妖  -为何一定要是小丑呢
- A leprechaun. - Why did it have to be clowns?
你有一堆小精灵在帮你
I'd say you have a bunch of elves working for ya.
仙女  得了吧
Fairies? Come on.
这是丘比特吗
This is Cupid?
天堂
Heaven.
-那是发着光的热乎乎的  -乳头吗
- It was a little glowing hot... - Nipples?
-裸女  -太让人不安了
- ...Naked lady. - Well, that's super disturbing.
我以前从没见过婴儿怪物
I've never seen a baby monster before.
为什么这么不愿相信上帝
Why is it so hard to believe that God
在让我看到一些关于黑暗的幻觉
could be sending me visions about the Darkness?
你究竟想告诉我什么
What are you trying to say?
别指望上帝  指望我们自己
Don't count on god. Okay? Count on us.
如果是上帝  那么他给我看的幻觉
If it is God, then he's showing me something
我不知道该怎么办  是笼子
I don't know what to do with -- the cage.
-路西法的笼子  -嗯
- Lucifer's cage? - Yeah.
如果他是告诉我  我必须回去怎么办
What if he's telling me I have to go back?
(如今)
(威斯康辛州  梅诺莫尼)
给你
Here you go.
一勺糖还是两勺
One spoonful of sugar or two?
麦迪  我和爸爸准备去吃饭了
Maddie, daddy and I are ready to go to dinner now.
等你准备好了  告诉我们
So whenever you're ready, you just let us know.
亮亮和我还没喝完茶呢  妈妈
Sparkle and me aren't done with tea, mommy.
那等你准备好了告诉我们
Well...When you're ready.
我们有预定呢
We have reservations.
育儿手册上说要耐心点
The R.I.E. manual says be patient.
那我们就等着她和假想朋友
So now we wait for her to have fake tea
喝完一顿假想的茶吗
with her fake imaginary friend?
太棒了
Perfect.
我们可以一直玩下去
We can party forever
让妈妈和爸爸吃麦圈当晚餐
while mommy and daddy eat cheerios for dinner.
没事的  麦迪
It's cool, Maddie.
跟你爸爸妈妈去吧  我来收拾
Go with your mom and dad. I'll clean up.
我爱你  亮亮
I love you, Sparkle.
麦迪
Hiya, Maddie!
你不是麦...
You're not Mad--
别忘记刷牙  亲爱的
Don't forget to brush your teeth, sweetie.
亮亮
Sparkle!
[邪恶力量 第11季第8集]
惊喜
Surprise!
你是谁
Who are you?!
是我啊  萨姆
It's me, Sam!
是萨利
It's Sully!
什么
What?
你记得我吧
You remember me, right?
我做了所有你最喜欢的零食
I-I made all your favorite snacks.
我们原来是好朋友  最好的朋友
We were friends. Like, best friends.
你记得吗
You remember?
-萨利  -嗯
- Sully. - Yeah.
不对  你不是真的
No. You're not real.
那你怎么能揍我呢
Well, how'd you punch me... then?
这不可能是真的
This can't be happening.
哥们
Dude.
你跟谁说话呢
Who you talking to?
他啊
Him.
你中风了吗
Are you having a stroke?
能闻到吐司味儿吗
Do you smell toast?
除非我想  他看不到我的
He can't see me unless I want him to.
这都是什么破烂啊
What is all of this crap?
你什么时候开始吃这些的
When'd you start eating this stuff?
那是粟米脆饼配棉花糖吗
Is that marshmallows on nachos?
这不是我做的
This wasn't me.
是我做的
It was me.
可好吃了
And those are delicious.
等等  你能看到他吗
Wait a second. C-can you see him?
迪恩  这
Dean, this, um...
这应该是萨利
I think this is...Sully,
我小时候的朋友
m-my friend from when I was a kid.
你是说这个吊裤带
You mean Mork from Ork here
是你的二逼幻想朋友萨利吗
is your dumbass imaginary friend Sully?
对
Yeah.
我才不二  也不逼呢
I'm not dumb or ass.
我去拿枪
I'm gonna get my gun.
不  别
No, please.
有人杀了我的朋友
Someone killed my friend.
你这幻想朋友的幻想朋友吗
You mean your imaginary imaginary friend?
首先  "幻想朋友"只是个描述性术语
First off, "imaginary friend" is more of a descriptive term.
但你刚刚说的方式  很冒犯人
How you just said it? That was a little...offensive,
我是实话实说
just to be honest.
其次  我们是赞纳
Secondly, we're Zanna.
我和...
Me and...
我和被害人都是赞纳
Me and the victim were Zanna.
我们帮助孩子  我们是好人
We help kids. We're the good guys.
萨姆  告诉他啊
Sam, tell him.
嗯  好吧
Yeah, okay.
知道吗  我还有点没从你是真的
You know what? I'm still trying to wrap my head around
这个震惊中缓过来呢
this whole you being real thing.
嗯  当然了  没事的
Yeah, no, no, of course. No, that's okay. That's okay.
这的确出乎意料
This is all really unexpected.
嗯  可以这么说吧
Yeah, that's one word for it.
我需要你们的帮助
Just...I need your help.
你们是猎人  这是你们的工作  是吧
All right, you're hunters. That's what you do, right?
你们是帮助他人的
I mean, you help people, too.
是啊  他"人"
Yeah. Yeah, people.
你不在这个范畴内
You are not that.
迪恩  拜托
Dean, come on.
拜托鬼  你开什么玩笑  看啊
Come on? Are you kidding... look...
这...我去...
This... mother--
你和我  图书馆  现在去
You and me, library, right now.
走
Come on!
嗯  我就待这儿好了
Yeah. No, I'll just stay here.
没问题
Coolio.
你不是真信他那套吧
You're not actually buying this crap, are you?
迪恩  我9岁的时候
Dean, when I was 9 years old,
你知道我最想要什么吗
you know what I wanted more than anything?
棉花糖粟米脆饼
Marshmallow nachos.
嗯  你小时候很怪
Yeah, you were a weird-ass kid.
嗯
Yeah, well...
我从来只跟一个人说过
The only person I ever told about it...
-就是萨利  -对
- Sully?  - Yes.
我不知道
I don't know, man. I...
或许  这是你的幻象
Hey, you know, maybe this is just one of your visions.
但我们都能看到
Yeah, except we're both seeing it.
而且跟笼子  路西法
And it doesn't involve the cage or Lucifer
或是我去跟笼子里的路西法说话无关
or me having to talk to Lucifer in the cage.
看啊  这里
Look at this. Here.
罗马尼亚传说中
In Romanian lore,
赞纳是指引保护迷失儿童的生物
Zanna are creatures who guide and protect lost children.
赞纳有意显现为孩子的臆想之物
Zanna intentionally appear as figments of a child's imagination,
等孩子不再需要指引时
allowing the child to move on with confidence
他们便让孩子自信地继续生活
once guidance is no longer necessary.
或许萨利说的是真的
Maybe Sully's telling the truth.
好吧  就算那个笨蛋是真的  好吗
Okay, say bozo is legit. Right?
虽然疯狂  但是好吧
Which, you know... hello, crazytown, but okay.
-这怎么跟我们有关了  -因为有人死了
- How is this our problem? - Because someone's dead.
不  是个生物死了
No, something is dead.
仙女教母被人杀了  跟我们无关
A fairy godmother getting capped? That ain't our beat.
-是  我知道  迪恩  但是  -但是什么
- Yes, I know that, Dean, but... - But what?
但是  虽然听上去很诡异很疯狂
But as messed up and insane as this sounds...
萨利帮过我
Sully helped me.
就是这里
That's the place.
里面可可怕了
It's a horror show in there.
你是说  你进去过吗
You mean, you've been inside?
昨晚
Last night.
我现在是管理层了
I'm in management now,
所以平时不怎么出外勤
so I don't get out in the field much.
我只是来见亮亮的
I just came to see Sparkle.
亮亮
Sp-- Sparkle?
嗯
Yeah.
我去了
Oh, I show up and...
结果那里一片狼藉
I mean, the place was bananas.
孩子报了警  妈妈吓坏了
Kid had called the cops, mom's freaking out,
亮亮
and...Sparkle...
萨姆  太可怕了
Sam, it was horrible.
好吧  由于赞纳的规矩
Okay, so according to Zanna rules,
只有孩子看到了  是吧
the kid is the only witness, right?
嗯
Yeah.
可怜的孩子
Oh, poor thing.
我们里面见
I'll meet you inside.
好吧  你想怎么办
All right, what are you thinkin'?
很好  扮成伯特和厄尼  太棒了
Good. The Bert and Ernie pretext. Awesome.
哥们  你不用非得来
Dude, you didn't have to come.
这幻想朋友什么的
You know, this whole imaginary friend thing
当年很蠢  现在也很蠢
was dumb then and it's dumb now.
嗯  你已经说得很明白了
Yeah, you've made that pretty clear.
你就没想过要告诉我他是真的吗
You didn't think to tell me that he was real?
迪恩  我没以为他是真的啊
Well, Dean, I didn't think he was.
而且你也看到传说书了
And you saw the lore book, too.
或许我9岁的时候
I mean, maybe when I was 9 years old
我以为他是真的  但我长大了
I thought he was real, but I grew up.
或者过了那个阶段了
Or grew out of it.
不管怎样  我放下了他
Whatever. I left it.
你为什么会需要那熊玩意啊
And what did you need Drop Dead Fred for in the first place?
我小时候很孤独的  迪恩
I was kind of a lonely kid, Dean.
你才不孤独呢  你还有我啊
You weren't lonely. You had me.
接啊  伙计
Go on, bud.
不管怎样  都没事的
Whatever happens, it's cool beans.
迪恩
Dean?
你问了吗
Did you ask?
嗯  不行
Yeah, it's not gonna happen.
拜托  你说过的
Come on. You said.
我说过会问  但爸爸说不行了
Look, I said I would ask. Dad said no.
我能怎么办啊
What do you want me to do about it?
但我有练习射击  我能跑两英里
But I've been shooting. I can run 2 miles.
我知道银能杀狼人
I know silver kills werewolves, and...
-萨姆  -不公平
- Sammy... - No fair.
你比我还小时就开始猎魔了
You started hunting when you were younger than me.
我可没有幻想朋友
Yeah, well, I never had an imaginary friend.
-我听到了  -我会继续磨老爸的
- I heard that. - Look, I'll keep working on dad, all right?
别听他的  萨姆  他坏死了
Don't listen to him, Sammy. He's a germ.
或许下次你可以跟来
Now maybe you can come next time.
好吧
Sure.
好了  我得挂了  过几天打给你
All right, I gotta go. Call you in a couple days.
嗯  我...
Yep, I'll just be...
就在这儿
...here.
好了  我们终于可以拿瓶子做火箭了
Hey, come on. We can finally make those bottle rockets.
是吧
Right?
-有事吗  -伯曼太太  我是斯特拉莫医生
- Can I help you? - Mrs. Berman, I'm Dr. Strummer.
-这位是我的同事  -麦克高文医生
- This is my associate... - Dr. MacGowan.
我们是儿童福利机构的创伤咨询师
We are trauma counselors with child services.
我们是来跟进昨天的一宗报警的
We're here to follow up on a police report filed yesterday?
那是...
That was...
请进吧
come in.
我女儿  麦迪  是她报了警
Uh, my daughter, Maddie, she's the one who called.
她的想象力很丰富
Uh, she has an active imagination.
她幻想出了一个独角兽男人  亮亮
She made up this unicorn man, Sparkle.
但是她觉得他死在她房间里了
But, um, she thinks he's dead in her room.
亮亮是个独角兽还男人吗
So Sparkle is a unicorn and also a man?
-嗯  -独角男喽
- Yeah. - So a manicorn.
是吧
I...I guess?
我们可以...
May we, uh...
-当然  请  谢谢  -好
- Yes, please. Thank you. - Great.
麦迪
Hey, Maddie.
我和我搭档想问问你昨晚的事
My partner and I would like to ask you about last night.
关于亮亮的事
About Sparkle?
你妈妈说你不想回你的房间
Your mom says you don't wanna go back into your room?
为什么
How come?
好多血
All of the blood.
她还是个婴儿时就睡这儿
This has been her room since she was a baby.
她一直喜欢这个房间  直到昨晚
She's loved this room. And then last night...
介意我们到处看看吗
Do you mind if we take a look around?
我就回来
I'll be right back.
-好吧  问题在哪  -不知道
- All right. What's the problem? - I don't know.
我都说很惨了
I told you it was horrible.
能让我们看看吗
You mind enlightening us?
如果我让你们看到我们能看到的
If I show you all we can see,
你们可不许说出去
you can't tell a soul.
嗯  妹子最喜欢听男人说什么幻想朋友了
Oh, yeah, 'cause chicks dig the whole imaginary friend thing.
好吧
Fine.
嗯  那孩子绝逼需要心理医生了
Oh, yeah. That kid is gonna need all the shrinks.
等等  他的血也是亮的吗
Wait a second. So his... blood is glittery?
就连死后  亮亮都还如此闪亮
Even when he's dead, Sparkle can't stop shining.
谁会做这种事
Who would do this?
是刀捅死的
It was a blade.
萨利  赞纳间互相能看到吗
Sully, can Zanna see other Zanna?
当然
Of course.
但不会像你想的那样
But it's not what you're thinking.
赞纳是干不出这种事的
A Zanna could never do this.
没什么可看的  是吧
Nothing to see, right?
我一直觉得
I was always under the impression
父母该尽量让孩子
that it was parent's job to let a child be a child
-保持童心  -这下不妙
- as long as possible. - Oh, this is bad.
或许我们太纵容她了
Maybe we let her get too carried away.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我是说
I mean...
叫亮亮的幻想朋友
an imaginary friend named Sparkle.
多可爱啊
What's cuter than that?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我这下跟我女儿一样小题大做了
I'm being as dramatic as my daughter now.
她脸上都沾上了  萨姆  她脸上
Um, it's on her face. Sam, it's on her face!
-告诉我  -她脸上沾了亮亮的血
- Just tell me. - She's got Sparkle on her face!
我们怎么唤回我们的女儿
How do we get our girl back?
谁说句话啊  谁赶紧说句话
Somebody's say something. Someone's gotta say something.
这样吧  你们有客房吗
You know what? Is there a spare bedroom?
太好了  或许该让麦迪住那儿  会好一点
Great. Uh, maybe Maddie can sleep there. That should help.
她脸上有血
It's on her face.
热水澡  对人大有益处
And a hot shower does wonders.
好好洗洗  净化一下
Real deep scrub. Purify.
-麦迪吗  -一家人都需要
- For Maddie? - The whole family.
大家一起去洗洗
Yeah, just get the whole gang in there.
一起洗澡的家庭...
You know, the family that showers together...
-住口  别说了  -好吧
- Pull up! Pull up. - Okay.
这样吧  先从这里开始
You know what? Why... why don't you start there?
如果需要更多指引可以联系我们办公室
You can contact our office for more guidance if you like.
好的
Okay.
天呐  佐伊  我好像也看到宝藏了
Oh, my gosh, Zoe, I think I saw the treasure, too!
我们去找吧
Let's go for it!
等等  你不是还得练体操吗
But wait, don't you have gymnastics?
嗯  等我回来再说吧
Oh, yeah. Let's look at it when I get back.
好
Right on.
妮琪昨晚没向总部报告
Nicky didn't check in with the home office last night.
这不可能
This can't be happening.
你们还能跟彼此说话
You gazoos can talk to each other?
我们赞纳有心灵感应
Us zanna share a telepathic link.
她不会在那儿的
She wouldn't be in there.
居然是美人鱼
A frickin' mermaid?
简直是屠杀
It's a bloodbath.
好了  哭出来吧
All right, just let it out.
不不
Uh, no. No.
我得为萨姆坚强一点
I gotta stay strong for Sam.
看来又是捅死的
Looks like more stabbing.
好吧  萨利  会有什么人
Okay, Sully, is there anybody
想伤害妮琪吗
that would want to hurt, uh, Nicky?
没有  不过...
No. Well...
怎么了
What?
她男友有点黏人
Oh, well, I mean, her boyfriend's a little clingy.
他是我最好的朋友之一啊
But he's one of my best friends.
伙计们  维慕斯绝不会伤害妮琪的
Guys, Weems would never hurt Nicky.
他太爱她了
I mean, he loved her too much.
太过也不是好事
Well, too much ain't good.
我们去找美人鱼的男友谈谈吧
So let's go talk to the mermaid's boyfriend,
幻想朋友还有男朋友了
because apparently, imaginary friends have boyfriends now.
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
我们不能把她丢这儿  会吓到孩子的
We can't just leave her here. It's disturbing for the kid.
好吧  那你要我们怎么办
All right, well, what do you wanna do?
找个大马桶把她冲走吗
Find a giant toilet and flush it?
好吧  我...
You're right. I was...
你希望我们做什么
What would you like us to do?
我刚刚好像看到铁锹了
I think I saw some shovels back there.
好吧
Okay.
龙猫还真在乎你啊
Well, Totoro really cares for you, huh?
好了  我想到了
Okay, I got one.
说吧
Hit me.
有没有想过
Ever think...
你会飞
you can fly?
有时候吧
Oh, sometimes.
风很大的时候
Like, on really windy days.
-你呢  -我以前想过
- You? - I used to,
但我摔断了胳膊
but I broke my arm.
-该你了  -好吧
- Your turn. - Okay.
有没有想过
Ever think...
你可以一下吃掉十个华夫饼
you could eat 10 waffles in one sitting?
希望等我长大了可以  你呢
Well, I hope so when I'm big. Can you?
我试过一次
I tried, once.
起来太快头晕了
Head rush.
有没有想过
Ever think...
逃跑
about running away?
逃离你吗  绝对不会
From you? No way.
不是  我是指  逃离这里
No. I mean, from here.
这一切
All this.
猎人的生活
The hunting life.
你呢
Do you?
有没有想过
Ever think...
或许你想去学校
that maybe you wanna go to school?
交些朋友
Make some friends?
但我有你啊
But I have you.
是的
Yeah, you do.
但有一天我就会不在了
But one day you won't.
萨姆  我需要你听好
Sam, I want you to listen to me.
你可以成为你想做的任何人
You can be whatever you wanna be.
你不是迪恩  你不是你爸爸
You're not Dean. You're not your dad.
你是萨姆
You're Sam.
而且萨姆好棒啊
And Sam is so awesome.
你能想象吗  离家出走
Can you imagine? Running away?
我爸会杀了我的
My dad would kill me.
这
Well...
这是你的选择  萨姆
It's your choice, Sam.
这是你的人生  这都要看你的决定
It's your life. I mean, it's all up to you.
好吧
Okay.
好吗
Okay?
我们走吧
Let's go.
懒鬼
Hey, slacker.
要我一个人埋了小美人鱼吗
Am I burying Ariel by myself here or what?
-不  嗯  -快点
- No. Yeah, of course. - Let's go.
你还好吗  萨利
How you holding up, Sully?
我没事
I'm fine.
你呢  萨姆
How are you, Sam?
很好
Aces.
别担心  孩子
Don't worry, kid.
人人都有尿尿的问题
Everybody's got a pee-pee problem.
维慕斯会处理好这些床单
Weems will take care of these sheets,
妈妈绝不会知道的
and mommy will be none the wiser.
如果妈妈听到了我们呢
What if mommy hears us?
弗莱彻  今晚就是有游行妈妈都不会醒了
Fletcher, not even a parade can wake mommy up tonight.
因为她喝了大人果汁睡过去了吗
Because she drank her grown-up juice and went sleepy-by?
是啊  妈妈今晚喝了好多果汁
Yep. Mommy drank a lot of juice tonight.
你想去睡吗
Hey, you wanna try and hit the sack?
好  我们上面见了  伙计
All right. I'll catch you on the flip side, okay, bud?
谢谢  维慕斯
Thanks, Weems.
不客气
You got it.
萨利
Sully!
Sully.
萨利
萨...
Sul--
萨利
Sully.
维慕斯  维慕斯  你没事吧
Weems! Weems, are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
刀扎透了我的腰间赘肉
It went right through my love handle.
我的肥肉救了我  能相信吗
My fat saved me. Can you believe that?
-肥肉最棒了  -嗯
- Fat is the best. - Yeah.
美人鱼就没那么幸运了
Yeah, well, the mermaid wasn't so lucky.
他在跟我说话吗
Is he talking to me?
他们是谁
Who are these guys?
是我的朋友
They're friends.
维慕斯  你最后见到美人鱼妮琪是什么时候
Hey, Weems, when was the last time you saw Nicky the mermaid?
天呐  真不敢相信我刚刚说了那句话
God, I can't believe I just said that.
昨天  怎么了
Yesterday. Why?
妮琪怎么了
What happened to Nicky?
她被杀了
She was murdered.
什么
What?!
维慕斯  我很遗憾
Weems, I am so sorry.
不  她是...我的女人啊
No! She... she was my girl!
亮亮也死了
Sparkle's gone, too.
不是吧  哥们  我们被灭团了啊
Not sparkle! Dude, that's, like, our whole posse.
是啊
I know, right?
但你没事啊  你没事
But hey, you're okay. You're okay.
好了  你们都是朋友
Okay, all right, so you're all pals.
有人会跟你们有仇吗
Is there anybody who would have beef with the bunch of you?
我从没见过她
I've never seen her before in my life.
等等  你看到人了吗
Wait a second. You saw somebody?
一个姑娘
Some chick.
她捅了我之后
After she...shivved me,
开着一辆老大众甲壳虫跑了
she took off in an old VW bug.
-我真难过  维慕斯  -这是好事吧
- I'm so sorry, Weems.  - So this is a good thing, right?
-不  这太棒了  -好恶心
- Uh, no, this is a great thing. I mean, - It's gross!
独角男  美人鱼
a manicorn? A freakin' mermaid?
这叫我怎么办
What am I supposed to do with that?
但开车的小妞  这是本行  我的地盘
But a chick in a car? That's terra firma. I'm home.
好吧  你去  我照顾他俩
All right, you go. I'll, uh, cover these two.
是啊  直接穿透了
It goes... it's... yeah, it goes all the way through.
我得问问
I gotta ask.
酸洗牛仔裤
Hey, uh, acid wash.
你有什么特别的
What's so special about you?
美人鱼喜欢我吗
Mermaids dig me?
不  孩子为什么喜欢你
No, I-I mean, why do kids like you?
我会弹幻想吉他
I play air guitar.
你弹幻想吉他
You play air guitar?
萨姆也弹幻想吉他  我也会
Sam plays air guitar. I can play air guitar.
没事
That's okay, it's okay.
-独奏真棒  -谢谢
- Good solo. Good solo. - Thanks.
他还是比不上克莱普顿
Well, he's no Clapton.
我去弄点绷带  好吗
You know, I'm gonna go get some bandages. Okay?
我就回来  萨姆
Oh, I'll be right back, Sam.
等等
Wait.
你不是那个萨姆吧
You're not that Sam?
萨利的萨姆
Sully's Sam?
大概是吧  嗯
I guess I would be. Yeah.
你和萨利现在又在一起了吗
So now you and Sully are, like, back together?
什么
What?
-你多大了  -不是的
- How old are you? - Wrong.
我懂的
Look, I get it.
我们时不时都需要调整下心情  没事的
We all need a tune-up from time to time. It's okay.
不是的  他来找我的
No. He, uh, came to me.
我是在帮他忙
I'm helping him out.
萨姆·温彻斯特
Sam Winchester.
我是说
I mean...
告诉你一声
Hey, just so you know...
萨利
Sully?
你伤透了他的心  哥们
You broke his heart, man.
准备好上路了吗
Ready to hit the road?
不  我爸爸刚打来了
No. My dad just called.
-是吗  -他改主意了
- Yeah? - He changed his mind.
他要我一起去了
He wants me to come with him.
去猎魔吗
On a... on a hunt?
终于啊  他觉得我准备好了
Finally! He thinks I'm ready.
我得赶下一趟大巴去密尔沃基
I have to catch the next bus to Milwaukee.
你真的想要这样吗
Are you sure this is what you want?
我是温家人  我是猎魔的
I'm a Winchester. I hunt monsters.
我怎么会想要别的
Why would I want anything else?
这未必适合你吧
Well, I-I'm not sure it's you.
你为什么不能替我开心呢  萨利
Why can't you be happy for me, Sully?
听我说  伙计
Listen, buddy,
我只是担心你在走上一条
I'm just afraid you're going down a path
你不该走的路
you might be better off not going down.
但我不怕
Yeah, but I'm not afraid.
我知道
I know you're not.
你是我见过的最勇敢的孩子之一了
You're one of the bravest kids I know.
只是...猎魔什么的
It's just... This whole hunting thing,
并不是唯一的出路
you know, it's not the only way.
还有很多其他出路  你能找到一条的  萨姆
There are so many other ways. And you can find one, Sam.
你可以现在就走
You can leave right now.
我不想走别的路
I don't want another way.
我想跟爸爸和迪恩在一起
I wanna be with my dad and... and Dean.
听我说  萨姆
Look, Sam,
我这么说只是因为我是你的朋友
I'm just saying this 'cause I'm your friend.
假想朋友
Pretend friend!
你都不是真的
You're not even real.
只要你需要我  我都在的
Well, I'm... I'm here as long as you need me.
我已经不需要你了  萨利
I don't need you anymore, Sully.
我都不知道我当初为什么要想象你出来
I don't even know why I made you up in the first place.
我希望你消失
I wish I could unmake you up.
如果你真是这么想的
If -- if that -- if that's what you want.
是的
It is, okay?
你走吧
Just go.
祝你度过美好长寿的一生  萨姆
You have a good, long life, sam.
干得不错
No, you did a good job.
-紧吗  -不紧
- Is it too tight? - No.
很好
All right, that's good.
好了  可以了  伙计
Okay. There you go, pal.
好
All right.
我去看看弗莱彻
I'm gonna go check on Fletcher.
那孩子老憋不住尿
Kid has a bladder like a sieve.
你真的很棒
You know, it's... pretty awesome,
这样帮助你身边的人
how you help everyone around you.
有时候结果并不好  不过
Doesn't always work out, but...
我会尽力
I try.
萨利
Sully...
我很过意不去
I feel awful.
我们当年分别时的情形
About how we left off.
抱歉  我当时还是个熊孩子
I'm sorry. I was a kid. I was a-a jerk kid.
你当时是想帮我
And -- and you were trying to help, and...
那是我的错
That's all on me.
我们总是要分别的  而我们的离别
I mean, goodbyes are part of the job, and ours was...
很糟糕
Pretty bad.
是很糟糕
Yeah. It was really bad.
我不骗你
You know, I'm not gonna lie to ya.
你跑去猎魔时
When you went off to hunt,
我把那当做我最大的失败之一
I considered that one of my biggest failures.
我当时真的觉得你想过别的生活
It just seemed so clear to me that you wanted something else.
可我想错了
But...I was wrong.
你这不做得挺好吗
And it all worked out, didn't it?
这倒未必
I don't know about that.
拜托
Come on.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
萨姆  你拯救了世界
Sam, you saved the world.
我一直关注着我的小朋友
I keep track of my kids.
你真的很棒  萨姆
And you did really good, Sam.
也不都好啦
Well...not all good.
我也做过些不好的事
There was some bad.
还有些非常不好的事
And some really bad.
萨利
Sully...
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
我把一样东西给放了出来
I let something out into the world that was...
你是说黑暗
You mean the darkness?
别人是这么说的
That's what the others are calling it.
我听到了一些流言
I've just heard rumors.
我一定会弥补的
Well, I'm gonna fix it. I am.
迪恩和我  我们会想办法的
Dean and I, we're -- we're -- we're gonna fix it.
只是
It's just...
怎么
What is it?
我觉得上帝想帮我们
I think God wants to help us fix it.
可是
But...
我觉得我做不到他要求我做的事
I don't think I can do what he's asking.
有多糟
How bad is it?
地狱里有个笼子
There's this cage in hell,
路西法被关在里面
and it's where they keep lucifer.
我也曾被关在里面
And I've been in it,
然后
and it's...
上帝好像想让我回到那里
and I think god wants me to go back.
有没有想过
Ever think...
逃离这一切
about running away anymore?
想过  不  我曾经想过
I did. Um, I mean, I have.
但好久没这样想了  现在不想了
But not in a while. Not anymore.
(找到她了  乔治大街1534号见  带上萨利)
有没有想过
Ever think...
偷一辆面包车
about hot-wiring a minivan?
梦里想过
In my dreams.
来吧
Let's do it.
(就来)
很好  你醒了
Good. You're awake.
你弟弟正在赶来
Your brother's on the way.
你谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我们似乎都认识同一个幻想朋友
I think we have a mutual imaginary friend.
你认识萨利吗
You know Sully?
慢着
Hold it.
瑞茜
Reese?
你好啊  陌生人
Hey, stranger.
把萨利交给我  我就把哥哥还你
You give me sully, I give you your brother.
你要对萨利做什么
What do you want with sully?
问他
Ask him.
他杀了我姐姐
He's the one who killed my sister.
那是意外
It was an accident.
什么
What?
瑞茜和她的双胞胎姐姐  是我以为
Reese and her twin sister, they were my first kids
跟你搞砸之后  接触的第一对孩子
after I thought I screwed things up with you.
-那么是他的错吗  -不是
- So this is his fault? - No!
不  瑞茜  是我搞砸了
No, Reese, I'm the one that bungled it.
是我
It was me.
我不该让她追着我到马路上
I should never have let her chase me into the street.
我们本来只是在玩捉人
We were just playing tag.
我不知道我为什么没看到有车来
I don't know why I didn't see the car coming.
所以我再也不想出外勤
That's why I never went back in the field.
再也没去找别的孩子
That's why I never found another kid.
我太害怕自己会伤到他们
I was too scared I'd hurt 'em.
你知道你给我带来多少痛苦吗
Do you know how bad you messed me up?
"奥德丽死了  都是因为隐形人"
"Audrey's dead because of the invisible man."
你试试对十个不同的儿童心理医生说这话
Try telling that to about 10 different kiddie shrinks.
我一直想知道萨利是不是真的
I always wondered if Sully was real,
于是我迷上了民间传说
so I got obsessed with folklore.
我出国去罗马尼亚学习  然后我发现
I studied abroad in Romania, and then I found out
他是赞纳
he's a Zanna.
是的  赞纳都是好人
Yes, and Zanna are good.
女巫也是这么告诉我的
That's what the witch tried to tell me, too.
-女巫  -她卖给我一个咒语
- The witch? - She sold me a spell
这样我就能够看到这些怪物
so that I'd be able to see these freaks.
她还给了我这个
She gave me this, too.
我终于能从这些怪物手上救下其他孩子
Finally, I can save other kids from these monsters.
你杀了我的朋友就是为了找到我
So you killed my friends just to get to me?
如果不是这俩人冒出来我还能更早找到你
And I would've done it sooner if these two hadn't shown up.
你为什么不召唤我  我会出现的
Why didn't you call? I would've come.
说实话  我挺喜欢看你痛苦的
Honestly, I kinda liked watching you suffer.
你不仅是奥德丽最好的朋友
You weren't just Audrey's best friend.
你也是我的
You were mine, too.
她死后  萨利
And after she died, Sully, I...
我当时最需要你
I never needed you more.
奥德丽死时  我慌了
I panicked when Audrey died,
我留下你自己面对痛苦
and I left you to deal with the pain
因为我不能接受这是我造成的惨剧
'cause I couldn't handle being the one that caused it.
所以也许我也夺走你的所爱  萨利
So maybe I'll take something you love, Sully --
一个真人
a real person.
别指望了
That's not gonna happen.
杀了我  会不会让你好受些
Will killing me make you feel better?
不  萨利  这不是解决办法
No, Sully, that's not the answer.
这是我的工作
This is what I do.
做对孩子最好的事
Whatever's best for the kid.
瑞茜
Reesy...
如果这是你需要的
if this is what you need,
我能接受
I'm okay with it.
我还是生气
I'm still mad.
我停不下来
I can't stop it.
我还是那么生气
I'm just still so mad!
瑞茜
Reese.
相信我  复仇
Trust me. Revenge?
不会让你好受的
Ain't gonna make you feel better.
我见过很多怪物
Listen, I have seen more than my share of monsters.
真正的怪物
And I mean real monsters.
很邪恶
Bad.
这些人
These guys?
他们就是《芝麻街》的泰瑞莎修女
These are Sesame Street Mother Teresas.
但我不在我弟弟身边时
But when I wasn't there for my little brother,
萨利在
Sully was.
我不是说他没有犯错
Now, look, I'm not saying that he didn't make a mistake,
但你知道他绝不是什么怪物
but you know that there is not a monstrous bone in his body.
我很抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
瑞茜  我很抱歉
Oh, Reesy, I'm so sorry.
既然你知道了奥德丽的事
Well, now that you know about Audrey,
你可能再也不想见到我了
you probably never wanna see me again.
有没有想过
Ever think...
或许你是我的英雄
maybe you're a hero to me?
-是吗  -萨利
- Yeah. - Sully...
我知道一件事
One thing I've learned --
英雄都不是完美的
Heroes aren't perfect.
有时候  他们也会害怕
Sometimes, they're scared.
但那是因为  他们所面对的事
But that just means the thing that they're facing,
超级重要
it's super important.
没有人其他人会去做
And nobody else is gonna go for it
因为其他人都没这胆量
because nobody else has got the balls.
又到了那个时刻了
Well, it is that time again.
你会去看着瑞茜吧
You, um, you'll look in on Reese?
别担心  我会去看她的
Don't worry. I will be checking in.
迪恩
And, Dean,
谢谢你帮我照看萨姆
thank you for looking out for Sam.
你一点都不坏
You are not a germ at all.
谢了
Thanks?
你永远也别想让我承认
You know, you're not gonna ever get me to admit
你不是最奇怪的东西
that you're not the weirdest thing out there,
不过
but, um...
你是好的奇怪
you're a good weird.
祝你好运  兄弟
Good luck, buddy.
我们走吧
Let's do it.
迪恩  我们需要认真讨论一下
Dean, we need to seriously discuss
我去笼子的事
me going to the cage.
好吧
Okay.
不可能的  谈话愉快
Not happening. Good talk.
萨姆  即使幻象是真的
Sam, even if these visions are real --
嗯  是路西法  和我
Yeah. It's Lucifer? And me?
在笼子里  我懂
In the cage? I know.
但这个  我的心结
But this -- this lump in my throat...
不再是个借口了
It's not an excuse, not anymore.
我们会找到其他办法
We'll find another way.
好吗  总有其他办法
Okay? There's always another way.
好吧
Okay.
那告诉我
Then tell me.
其他办法是什么
What is the other way?